Guide to the Ford E. and Harriet R. Curtis Theatre Collection of Pittsburgh Performing Arts Photographs, 1914-present CTC.1966.03
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Ford E. and Harriet R. Curtis Theatre Collection of Pittsburgh Performing Arts Photographs
1914-present
CTC.1966.03
ULS Archives & Special Collections
1160.0 photographs
Within the Ford E. and Harriet R. Curtis Theatre Collection of Pittsburgh Performing Arts Photographs are over one thousand images related to the history of the performing arts in Pittsburgh. They include images of Pittsburgh theatre venues and local arts groups' production photos.
Curtis, Ford E., 1896-1979
Curtis, Harriet R., d. 1971
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Related Material
Pittsburgh City Photographer Collection, 1901-2002, AIS.1971.05, Archives & Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Ford E. and Harriet R. Curtis Theatre Collection of Performing Arts Photographs (finding aid in-progress)
History
Ford E. and Harriet R. Curtis Theatre Collection has amassed a large collection of photographs related to the performing arts. Within that collection are over one thousand photos and other types of images related to Pittsburgh. The majority of these photographs were acquired through numerous donations from members of the press or the local performing arts groups themselves. They include images of Pittsburgh theatre venues and local arts groups' production photos.
Accruals
Donations are occasionally added to the collection. These donations come from the producing groups themselves or members of the press. If you are interested in donating photographs to the collection, please contact the Special Collections Department staff.
Scope and Content Notes
The Pittsburgh performing arts photographs are interfiled within the Curtis Collection's larger preforming arts photograph collection. For the most part the collection consists of 8 x 10" or 5 by 7" photographic prints, however, there is also a small amount of negatives, slides, digital images, etc. All of the photographs are arranged in one large alphabetical system. This finding aid was written and the photos were categorized into three series (People, Productions, and Theatres) to facilitate researcher browsing.
Previous Citation
Ford E. and Harriet R. Curtis Theatre Collection of Pittsburgh Performing Arts Photographs, 1907-present, CTC.1966.03, Curtis Theatre Collection, Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh
Arrangement
The collection is organized into three series.
Series I. Productions, 1938-2011
Series II. Theatres, 1914-1980
Series III. People and Miscellaneous, 1914-2007
Architecture; Architecture -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Buildings -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh -- Photographs; Performing arts -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Pittsburgh (Pa.) -- Photographs; Theater -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh
- Productions, 1938-2011; I.; 1021.0 photographs
  Scope and Content Notes
  Contained in this series are images from theatre productions by Pittsburgh-related performing arts groups. Each item contains a scope note that details the individuals in the photograph, who produced the production, and when and where the production took place. Please note that this series does not contain images from touring productions that were produced in Pittsburgh. Images from touring productions can be found in the Touring series within the Ford E. and Harriet R. Curtis Theatre Collection of Performing Arts Photographs. The majority of the photos date from the early 1970s through the early 2000s. The series is arranged alphabetically by the production title. When there are multiple productions of the same play, the producing group is identified in the title and the scope note.
  - The 5th of July, July 8-25, 1982; 1.0 photograph
    This folder contains one photograph of Soho Repertory Theatre's production of The 5th of July including Nancy Breshock as Shirley Talley and Joe DeSmo as Ken Talley.
  - 57 by Two, 1980; 1.0 photograph
    57 by Two was presented by the Iron Clad Agreement in April 1980. Photograph is of K. Wilson Hutton and Mark Harlow.
  - 6 RMS RIV VU, 1987; 2.0 photographs
    These two photographs show Curt DeBor, Thom McLaughlin, Cynthia Nelson, and Denise Pullen in the Tonidale Dinner Theatre's production of 6 RMS RIV VU. It was performed April 1st through May 8th, 1987.
  - Abie's Irish Rose, 1.0 photograph
    This file contains one photograph from Comtra Theatre's production of Abie's Irish Rose. Appearing in the photo are actors Barry Pile, Sharon Schultz, and Bob Boduch. The play was performed in October and November of an unknown year.
  - The Adventures of Tom Sawyer and Huckleberry Finn, 2002; 1.0 photograph
    The Adventures of Tom Sawyer and Huckleberry Finn was presented by Mountain Playhouse from August 6-18, 2002. Photograph is of Trey Compton and Eric Wheeler.
  - Ah, Wilderness!, September 2007; 5.0 photographs (on CD-R disc)
    This file contains a CD-R disc with 5 images from the Pittsburgh Playhouse Repertory Company's production of Ah, Wilderness!. The play was performed September 6-23, 2007. The images show actors Larry John Meyers, Joel Ripka, Penelope Miller Lindblom and several other members of the cast.
  - Ain't Misbehavin', 1992; 1.0 photograph
    This photograph is from a production of Ain't Misbehavin' at Shenley High School in 1992. Appearing in the photo are Devon Wyman, Sabrina Gutierrez, Shakea Hundley, Johanne Rapp, Kaycee Mitchell, and Kelly Stuart. The photographer was Neretta J. Troxell.
  - Alice in Wonderland, 1980-1981; 1.0 photograph
    Alice in Wonderland was presented by Theatre Express from December 4, 1980 - January 4, 1981. Photograph is of Janet Reed and Jason Moehring.
  - All About Love and Other Fantasies, 1972; 3.0 photographs
    All About Love and Other Fantasies was presented by the White Barn Theatre from June 20 - July 1, 1979. Photographs are of Art Shawn, Patricia Lipton, and Jerry Morris.
  - Alms for the Middle Class, 1983; 6.0 photographs
    Alms for the Middle Class was presented by Pittsburgh Public Theater from February 3 - March 20, 1983. Photographs are of Richard Greene, Marcus Diamond, Timothy Donoghue, Evalyn Baron, Bethany Faye Decof, and Marshall Gaines.
  - Alone Together, October 1993; 1.0 photograph
    Photograph is of Larry John Meyers, Judy Baird, Seth Barrish, Jase Draper, Tamara Barron, and Neil Young in Alone Together. This Mountain Playhouse production played from October 6-17, 1993.
  - Always... Patsy Cline, 2001-2002; 3.0 photographs
    Always... Patsy Cline was presented by Mountain Playhouse in October 2001 and June 2002. Photographs are of Mimi Bessette and Mary Ehlinger.
  - American Buffalo, 1989; 1.0 photograph
    American Buffalo was presented by City Theatre from October 4 - November 5, 1989. Photograph is of Lamont Arnold, David Butler, and Bingo O'Malley.
  - Anastasia, 1979; 1.0 photograph
    Anastasia was presented by Robert Morris College Colonial Theater from March 29 - April 7, 1979. Photograph is of Sally Irwin and Victoria Falco.
  - Androcles and the Lion - Allegheny Repertory Theatre, 1981-1982; 1.0 photograph
    This photograph shows cast members Kirk Holtzinger, Speros Neforos, and Greg Rooney. This Allegheny Repertory Theatre production was on tour through the summer of 1981 till the spring of 1982.
  - Androcles and the Lion - Pittsburgh City Players, 1976; 1.0 photograph
    Androcles and the Lion was presented by the Pittsburgh City Players from July 6 - August 14, 1976.
  - Androcles and the Lion - Pittsburgh Playhouse, 1997; 1.0 photograph
    Photograph is of Shaun Ozminski and Angie Lovell in Androcles and the Lion. This production was a part of the Pittsburgh Playhouse's and Point Park College's Playhouse Jr. Series and played from February 22 - April 13, 1997.
  - Annie, 1995; 2.0 photographs
    Photographs are of Brigid Lavery, Jessica McKenzie, Amy Presuhn, Jeannie Cascio, Jennifer Beth May, Sarah Daniels, Lisa Kirschman, Katie Stiteler, Chrissy Klemens, Allison Davies, and Danielle Miller in Annie. This Mountain Playhouse production played from July 18 - August 6, 1995.
  - Annie, 1996; 2.0 photographs
    Headshot of Marcia Lewis who stared as Miss Hannigan in the Civic Light Opera's 1996 production of Annie.
  - Anything Goes, 1995; 2.0 photographs
    Cast photograph from Anything Goes at the Community College of Allegheny County's South Campus Theatre. Pictured are John Burja, Mary Brady, Colleen Cosgrove, and Brett Kitko. The play was performed at the South campus from June 9th through July 1st, 1995.
  - Arcadia, 1996; 1.0 photograph
    This cast photo of the Pittsburgh Public Theater's Arcadia includes Harry O'Toole, Dan Fassio, Martin Giles, Deborah Kipp, Gretchen Cleevely, David Conrad, and John Hall. This production played from April 18 - May 26, 1996.
  - Arms and the Man, 1995; 1.0 photograph
    Photograph is from a scene from the romantic comedy Arms and the Man at the Mountain Playhouse which played from September 20 - October 1, 1995. Pictured are Michele Schmitt, Dann Fink, and Michael McEachran.
  - Arsenic and Old Lace - Community College of Allegheny County, 1.0 photograph
    Photograph of a scene from Arsenic and Old Lace at the Community College of Allegheny County's South Campus Theatre. Pictured are J.R. Hall, Dale Irvin, and Kenneth Hall.
  - Arsenic and Old Lace - Comtra Theatre, 1991; 1.0 photograph
    This file contains one photograph from Comtra Theatre's production of Arsenic and Old Lace. Appearing in the photo are actors Marie Teets, Philip Bauer, and Betty Tolbert. The play was performed October 31st through November 16th, 1991.
  - Arsenic and Old Lace - Duquesne University, 1984; 1.0 photograph
    Arsenic and Old Lace was presented by Duquesne University from February 1-14, 1984. Photograph is of Susan Vitulli, Timothy Irr, and Elaine Chojnicki.
  - Art - Little Lake Theatre Company, 2001; 1.0 photograph
    Yasmina Reza's Art was performed by the Little Lake Theatre Company September 27th through October 6th, 2001. The photograph shows actors Rom Rihn, Mark D. Yochum, and Art DeConciliis.
  - Art - Mountain Playhouse, 2001; 1.0 photograph
    Art was presented by Mountain Playhouse from September 5-16, 2001. Photograph is of Nick Ruggeri, Tom Schaller, and Douglas Rees.
  - Art/Work, 1981; 2.0 photographs
    Art/Work was presented by the Iron Clad Agreement from January 22 - February 1, 1981. Photographs are of Ann Beigel, Larry John Meyers, and Wilson Hutton.
  - At This Evening's Performance, 1.0 photograph
  - Avenue X, 1996; 1.0 photograph
    Photograph is of Kim Director, Alan Souza, Don Marshall, Hallam Banfield, Etta Cox, Robert Fire, Robert Jay Cronin, and Thos Shipley in Avenue X. This City Theatre production played from November 29 - December 22, 1996.
  - Awake and Sing, 1997; 1.0 photograph
    Photograph is of Christopher Conner and Fred Coehlier in Awake and Sing. This Carnegie Mellon production played during their 1996-1997 season.
  - Babes in Arms, 2.0 photographs
    Babes in Arms was presented by the Community College of Allegheny County from August 3-26, 1984. Photographs are of Denise Pullen, Dave Cabor, John Greeno, and Janet Ross.
  - Bad Habits, 1983; 2.0 photographs
    Bad Habits was presented by the Pittsburgh Laboratory Theatre from June 3-25, 1983. Photographs are of Patty Pelcz, Barbara Whitney, Tom Spanedda, and Bob Wenzel.
  - Balyasnikov, 1977-1978; 7.0 photographs
    Balyasnikov was presented by the Pittsburgh Public Theater from December 21, 1977 - January 22, 1978. Photographs are of Aleksei Arbuzov, Wanda Bimson, and Joseph Wiseman.
  - Barefoot in the Park - Fox Chapel Community Players, 1975; 1.0 photograph
    This folder contains one photograph of Fox Chapel Community Player's production of Barefoot in the Park including Jack Isalg as Velasco and Candy Eisengart as Corie.
  - Barefoot in the Park - Mountain Playhouse, 1994; 1.0 photograph
    Barefoot in the Park was presented by Mountain Playhouse from October 5-16, 1994. This photograph is of lead cast members, Michael William McCarty and Jennifer Laura Thompson.
  - Barefoot in the Park - White Barn Theatre, 1984; 1.0 photograph
    Barefoot in the Park was presented by the White Barn Theatre from June 7-30, 1984. Photograph is of cast members Karen Gergely, Pip Theodor, Carl Hetrick, and Johnette Sullivan.
  - Barnum, 1982; 2.0 photographs
    Barnum was presented at the Stanley Theatre from August 10-15, 1982. Photographs are of the Broadway company cast members.
  - Beast on the Moon, 1996; 1.0 photograph
    Photograph is of Faran Tahir, Vilma Silva, and Bill Thunhurst in Beast on the Moon. This City Theatre production played from February 23 - March 17, 1996.
  - Beau Jest, 1993; 1.0 photograph
    Beau Jest was presented by Mountain Playhouse from June 1-13, 1993. Photograph is of Nick Ruggeri, Janet Dickinson, and Michael McCarty.
  - Beaver Coat, 1977; 1.0 photograph
    Beaver Coat was presented by Carnegie-Mellon University from June 23 - July 9, 1977 at the Kresge Theatre. This photograph shows Susan Peretz and M.B. Miller.
  - A Bedful of Foreigners, 1983; 1.0 photograph
    A Bedful of Foreigners was presented by Mountain Playhouse from June 14-26, 1983. Photograph is of Tim Sheahan and Helen Eckard.
  - Bedroom Farce, September 1984; 1.0 photograph
    This photograph is of actors John R. McLaughlin and Martha Gronsky Ranii. The Orchard Performing Arts production was staged at the Apple Hill Playhouse in September, 1984.
  - Beehive, May 1995; 4.0 photographs
    Photographs from Gargaro Production's Beehive at the Fulton Theater. Pictured are Tammy Flodine, Etta Cox, Rema Webb, Sandra Rae Dowe, and Maria Beycoates-Bey.
  - The Beggar's Opera, 1976; 1.0 photograph
    The Beggar's Opera was presented by the Pittsburgh City Players from January 21 - February 21, 1976. Photograph is of unidentified cast members.
  - Bent, 1982; 1.0 photograph
    Bent was presented by the Pittsburgh Laboratory Theatre from January 15 - February 14, 1982. Photograph is of Ray Leghart and Bingo O'Malley.
  - Berlin to Broadway with Kurt Weill, 1981; 1.0 photograph
    Berlin to Broadway with Kurt Weill was presented by Carnegie-Mellon University from February 5-15, 1981 at the Studio Theatre. This photograph is of Christine Deveau, David Pevsner, and Karen Babcock.
  - The Best Little Whorehouse in Texas - Civic Light Opera, 1987; 1.0 photograph
    The Best Little Whorehouse in Texas was presented by the Civic Light Opera from August 4-9, 1987. Photograph is of Jaye P. Morgan and George Ball.
  - Betrayal, 2001; 1.0 photograph
    Betrayal was presented by the Quantum Theatre in October 2001, at the South Side's Terminal Buildings. The play was performed along with another Harold Pinter play, The Collection. This photograph includes actors Karla Boos and John Shepard. Photographs are by DJ Case.
  - Bible Herstory, 1983; 1.0 photograph
    Bible Herstory was presented by Chatham College on October 14 and 15 at the Eddy Theatre. This photograph is of Jannie Wolff and Fanale.
  - Big Bad Burlesque, 1977-1978; 1.0 photograph
    This photograph shows cast members Tracy Keenan and Mark Biertempfel. Big Bad Burlesque was a Don Brockett production performed throughout the 1970s.
  - Big Mother, 1976; 2.0 photographs
    Big Mother was presented by the Pittsburgh Laboratory Theatre from June 3 - July 3, 1976. Photographs are of Vince Vok, Nancy Friedman, and Ramona Fischer.
  - Big River, January 1997; 4.0 photographs
    Included in this file are four publicity photographs for Gargaro Production's Big River. Appearing in the photos are Christian Delcroix, John F. Proctor, III, and Anthony Marino. The production was performed at the Byham Theatre, January 15-21, 1997.
  - The Birthday Party, 2006; 2.0 photographs
    This folder contains two images from the 2006 Pittsburgh Playhouse Repertory Company's production of The Birthday Party. The first image features John Shepard as Goldberg and Jarrod DiGiorgi as Stanley. The second image features John Capodice as Petey and John Shepard as Goldberg. Photos courtesy of Drew Yenchak, Lighthouse Photography.
  - The Blacks, 1976; 6.0 photographs
    This folder contains six photographs of Demundi Production's The Blacks. The photographs include Birl McCord as Archibald, Cinde Ellzy as Virtue, Wadina Daniels as Africa, Sandy Alexander as The Victim, and Producer-Director Frederick Louis Richardson Jr.
  - Black Cycle, April 1976; 7.0 photographs
    This folder contains seven photographs from Demundi Productions presentation of Black Cycle at the Hill House, Kaufmann Program Center Auditorium April 1976.
  - Blithe Spirit, 1.0 photograph
    This folder contains one photograph of the Cabaret Theatre's production of Blithe Spirit and includes Janet Robb as Ruth, Kim Schraf as Elvira, and John J Carosella as Charles.
  - The Boor, 1980; 1.0 photograph
    The Boor was presented by the Pittsburgh Metropolitan Stage Company from May 21 - June 8, 1980. Photograph is of Shirley Tannenbaum and Jim Boerlin.
  - Born Yesterday, 1976; 1.0 photograph
    Born Yesterday was presented by the White Barn Theatre from June 29 - July 10, 1976. Photograph is of Ray Leghart and Joe Matrozza.
  - Botanica, November 1994; 1.0 photograph
    Photograph is of Ana Margarita Martinez-Casado, Ofelia Gonzalez, and Iliana Guibert in Repertorio Espanol's production of Botanica by Dolores Prida.
  - Le Bourgeois Avant-Garde, 1990; 1.0 photograph
    Photograph from a scene of Le Bourgeois Avant-Garde at the City Theatre, November 14 - December 16, 1990. Pictured are David W. Huffman and Robin Walsh.
  - The Boyfriend, 1979; 1.0 photograph
    The Boyfriend was presented by the South Park Conservatory Theatre from June 13-29, 1980. Photograph is of Mary Windstein and Rick Campbell.
  - The Boyfriend, 2.0 photographs
    This folder contains two photographs of the Oliver Plaza Dinner Theatre production of The Boyfriend.
  - Breaker Morant, 2002; 3.0 slides
    Appearing in these images are David Cabot as Lt. Harry ("Breaker") Morant, Mark Staley as Lt. Peter Hancock, and Michael Tornetta as Lt. George Witton. Breaker Morant was performed by the Pittsburgh Playhouse Repertory Company from November 8th through December 8th, 2002. The photographs were taken by Lighthouse Photography.
  - Breakfast with Les and Bess, 1996; 1.0 photograph
    Photograph is of Betty McKinley and David Garwood in Breakfast with Les and Bess. This Mountain Playhouse production played from June 25 - July 7, 1996.
  - Breakfast with Mugabe, February 2008; 17.0 photographs (on CD-R disc)
    This file contains a CD-R disc with 17 images from Quantum Theatre's production of Breakfast with Mugabe. The play was performed February 7- 24, 2008 at Piatt Place in downtown Pittsburgh.
  - Breaking the Silence, 1983; 1.0 photograph
    Breaking the Silence was presented by Chatham College on November 20 and 21, 1983 at the Chatham College Woodland Playroom. This photograph is of cast members Danna Bigenho and Doris Johnson.
  - Brigadoon, 1995; 2.0 photographs
    Appearing in these photos are Lisa Delmar as Meg Brockie, Vaughn A. Challingsworth as Jeff Douglas, Amanda Slaughter as Fiona MacLauren, Jonathan Surmacz as Tommy Albright, and Gerrard Spencer as Mr. Lundie. Brigadoon was performed by the Point Park College Theatre Company from October 18th through November 5th, 1995.
  - Broadway at Hartwood, August 1996; 1.0 photograph
    This file contains one photograph with Gargaro Productions actors Anthony Marino, Renata Carreon, Warren Shirer, and Missy Schmotzer. They appeared in Broadway at Hartwood in August 1996.
  - Broadway at Hartwood, 1997; 2.0 photographs
    This file contains two photograph with Gargaro Productions actors Peter Smith, Jason Michael Swauger, Anthony Marino, and Missy Schmotzer. They appeared in Broadway at Hartwood from July 30th through August 17, 1997.
  - Broadway at Hartwood, August 2001; 1.0 photograph
    This file contains one photograph with Pittsburgh Musical Theater actors Renata Marino, Anthony Marino, and Cavan Pamer. They appeared in Broadway at Hartwood in August 2001. Photograph by Patti Brahim.
  - Broadway Bound, 2003; 2.0 photographs
    Broadway Bound was presented by Mountain Playhouse from September 3-14, 2003. Photographs are of Chan Harris and Jeffrey Correia.
  - Brockett & Barbara & Friends, 1986; 1.0 photograph
    This photograph includes cast members Marti George, Joyce Levenson, Michael Safran, Howard Elson, Barbara Russell, and Don Brockett. The musical revue opened at the Green Tree Marriott's Dinner Theatre on-the-Green on July 17th, 1986.
  - Bullshot Crummond, 1981; 1.0 photograph
    This photograph shows cast members of Bullshot Crummond. Included in the photos are Robert Koch and John Waterson. The Fine Line Theatre Company play was performed at the Soho Theatre in Oakland January 30th through February 22nd, 1981.
  - Burlescapade, 1983; 2.0 photographs
    Don Brockett's musical comedy revue opened July 8th, 1983 at the Green Tree Marriott hotel. Photos include performers Dawn Levendusky, Becky Timms, Michelle Murlin-Gardner, Heather Berman, Katie McCombs, and Paul Zielinski.
  - Burlesque Gaieties, 1975; 1.0 photograph
    Don Brockett's revue was performed at the Ben Gross Restaurant's Canterbury Room during the Summer of 1975. Photos include performers Neil Kugen, Georgia Meyers, Bob Bost, Maggie Stewart, Lynn Guerriero, Larry Broadright, Wendy Schlegel, Pam Hellett, Kathi O'Brian, and Philip Miscimarra.
  - Burn This, 1990; 2.0 photographs
    These photographs include David Butler, Helena Ruoti, Peter Webster, Kevin Donovan, and Lee Sankowich. This Pittsburgh Public Theater production played at the Theodore L. Hazlett, Jr. Theatre from April 5 - May 13, 1990.
  - Bus Stop, 2.0 photographs
    This folder contains two photographs of Play it Again Theatre Company's production of Bus Stop. The first photo includes Russ Meinert and Kathy Flocarri. The second photo includes Valerie Violi and Gregory Charles.
  - The Business of Murder, 1994; 1.0 photograph
    The Business of Murder was presented by Summer Theater-by-the-Grove at Indiana University of Pennsylvania from June 23 - July 2, 1994. Photograph is of Heather L. Cummings and Peter Curren.
  - The Butler Did It, 1982; 1.0 photograph
    The Butler Did It was presented by the South Park Conservatory Theatre from July 9-25, 1982. Photograph is of Mary Ann Varkonda and Gregory Charles.
  - Butterflies Are Free, 1979; 1.0 photograph
    Butterflies Are Free was presented by Robert Morris College Colonial Theatre from August 9-18, 1979. Photograph is of Nancy Schlossberg and Jeffri Theys.
  - Butterflies Are Free - Holiday Inn Irwin, 1.0 photograph
    This folder contains one photograph of the Holiday Inn Irwin's production of Butterflies are Free including Doris Schurr and Janey Potts.
  - Cabaret, 1974; 1.0 photograph
    Cabaret was presented by Camelot Productions from November 15 - December 1, 1974 at the Plaza Theatre. This photograph is of Demetria Ridosh.
  - Cabaret Verboten, 1992; 1.0 photograph
    Cabaret Verboten was presented by City Theatre from October 9 - November 8, 1992. Photograph is of Lenora Nemetz and Julia Collins.
  - California Suite, 1980; 1.0 photograph
    California Suite was presented by the White Barn Theatre from July 8-19, 1980. Photograph is of cast members Paul Mooney, Bruce Hoffman, Ken Miller, Renie Stevens, Carol Miller, and Michelle McCarthy.
  - Camelot, 1978; 4.0 photographs
    Camelot was presented by the Camelot Productions at the Plaza Theatre from January 20 - February 12, 1978. The photographs show cast members including Howard Elson, Linda Johnson, Jerry Comunale, Jr., and Bill Beck.
  - Camelot, 1.0 photograph